Matthew M. Lipphardt

Titusville, Florida 32780

Phone: 321-663-1251 | Email: <u>matthewlipphardt@gmail.com</u> **Linkedin**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-lipphardt-8b2356135/

> <u>**Github**</u>: <u>https://github.com/Mlipphardt</u> <u>**Portfolio**: https://github.com/Mlipphardt/Portfolio</u>

SUMMARY:

Web developer excited to utilize skills from a background in behavior analysis to create, optimize, and maintain server-side logic for efficient applications. Agile learner capable of grasping new concepts and languages quickly. Skilled at data collection, analysis, and adapting systems accordingly. My experience in collaboration and technical acumen will make me an invaluable asset to have on your team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python

Libraries/Frameworks: MySQL, Sequelize, node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, React.js, Bootstrap,

¡Query, AWS, TypeScript, MomentJS, Materialize, Django, Handlebars

Skills: REST APIs, Agile development, ORM, test-driven development, MVC

PROJECTS

Haggle Haus

Haggle Haus on Github: https://github.com/cgrady3/
Haggle Haus Live: https://haggle-haus.herokuapp.com/login

- Haggle Haus is a bartering marketplace where users can create accounts and post items to trade.
 Users can look at and accept bids on their own items, whilst also making offers on the items of other users.
- Constructed the API routes and MySQL queries for posting items and bids, populated the offers on the storefront, populated the item and bid trackers on the user profile pages, and created forms with front-end JavaScript for posting items and bids.
- The app's construction involved extensive use of MySQL and JQuery. Node.js was used for the server, and Sequelize was used as the app's main ORM.

Fanfixx

Fanfixx on Github: https://github.com/Mlipphardt/Fanfixx
Fanfixx Live: https://mlipphardt.github.io/Fanfixx/

- Fanfixx allows users to search for an athlete and receive their upcoming game schedules, current stats, biographic information, and also recent social media posts.
- Created the initial wireframe, the modal popup, handled all API requests for sports statistics and their display to the user.
- Extensive use of jQuery, in particular ajax API requests, CSS with Bootstrap and Materialize

Deep Sea Memory Game

<u>Deep Sea Memory Game on Github:</u> https://github.com/Mlipphardt/Memory-Game
<u>Deep Sea Memory Game Live:</u> https://mlipphardt.github.io/Memory-Game/

- Deep Sea Memory Game invites players to try to click on each of the pictures of deep sea animals, without repeating any of their selections. The game tracks score, and resets if the user clicks the same animal twice.
- React is the basis of this application, CSS using flexbox grid, Fischer-Yates algorithm.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: UCF Coding Bootcamp, Orlando, FL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical proficiency in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js and ReactJS. Graduated May, 2020.

Bachelor of Science, General Psychology: UCF, Orlando, FL

Graduated summa cum laude, December, 2016.

EXPERIENCE

Board-Certified assistant Behavior Analyst Eastern Florida Autism Center

2018-2020

Palm Bay, FL

Collaborated with a treatment team to collect data about clients, analyze it, and construct a behavioral intervention strategy. Trained registered behavior technicians, clients, and their caretakers regarding the plan and adjusted the plan continuously according to collected data.

Registered Behavior Technician2017–2018Eastern Florida Autism CenterPalm Bay, FL

Registered Behavior Technician2014–2017Positive Behavior Supports CorporationPalm Bay, FL